Be afraid. Be kind of afraid.
Scooby-Doo is a mystery, adventure, comedy film directed by Raja Gosnell.
When the Mystery Inc.
gang is invited to Spooky Island, a popular amusement park, they soon discover
that the attractions aren't the only things that are spooky.
Strange things are happening, and it's up to Scooby, Shaggy, Fred, Daphne, and
Velma to uncover the truth behind the mysterious happenings.
Fred, played by Freddie Prinze Jr..
Daphne, played by Sarah Michelle Gellar.
Shaggy, played by Matthew Lillard.
Velma, played by Linda Cardellini.
Scooby Voice (voice), played by Neil Fanning.
Mondavarious, played by Rowan Atkinson.
Scooby-Doo (also known as Scooby-Doo: The Movie) is a 2002 American comedy
horror film, based on the long-running animated franchise.
The first installment in the Scooby-Doo live-action film series, the film
was directed by Raja Gosnell and written by James Gunn.
It features an ensemble cast consisting of Freddie Prinze Jr., Sarah Michelle Gellar, Matthew Lillard, Linda
Cardellini and Rowan Atkinson, along with Neil Fanning providing the voice of the titular character.
The plot revolves around Mystery, Inc., a group of young adult
sleuths and their talking Great Dane who solves mysteries.
They reunite after a two-year disbandment to solve a mystery involving a series
of paranormal events at a horror-themed tropical island resort.
Filming took place in and around Queensland,
Australia, on a budget of $84 million.
Reggae artist Shaggy and rock group MxPx performed different
versions of the Scooby-Doo, Where Are You!
theme song for the film.
Scooby-Doo was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures on June 14, 2002, and was a commercial success,
grossing $275.7 million on a $84 million budget.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics.
The Scooby-Doo Spooky Coaster, a ride based on the
film, was built at Warner Bros.
Movie World on the Gold Coast, Queensland that same year.
A sequel, Scooby-Doo 2: Monsters Unleashed, was released in 2004.
Both films later gained a cult following.
The film explores themes of voodoo, detective,
talking dog, based on cartoon, resort.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.